Offline OCR — a safe, fully offline region-select OCR.
It's incredibly simple to use.
Just drag your mouse over the text you want to OCR.
The National Diet Library's OCR technology recognizes text right inside your browser.
The result is automatically copied to your clipboard. Ready to paste.
Fully offline. Optimized for Japanese. Supports vertical text. One-click launch.
Let's look at the key features.
All processing happens inside your browser. No data is ever sent externally. Powered by a high-accuracy engine developed by the National Diet Library of Japan.
Supports both horizontal and vertical Japanese text, including old books. Launch from the toolbar, keyboard shortcut, or right-click menu.
Auto-clean OCR results with custom regex rules. The UI automatically switches between Japanese and English.
About privacy. This extension never sends your data anywhere.
Screenshots, the OCR engine, AI models, and results — everything stays in your browser.
Communication with external servers is completely blocked. No images or text are transmitted.
Zero network requests. Zero data collection. It works even without an internet connection.
Let's look at the cleaning rules feature.
You can auto-format OCR results with regex before copying. Add, reorder, and toggle rules freely.
For example, invoice amounts. The raw OCR data contains commas and spaces...
Apply the rules, and the result is cleaned up into plain numbers.
Here's how it works under the hood.
The Content Script displays the selection UI and sends coordinates to the Service Worker.
The Service Worker captures a screenshot and forwards it to the OCR Worker.
ONNX Runtime Web runs local inference.
The result is sent back and written to the clipboard. All running locally on Manifest V3.